A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Fairness in irrigation development: a review of Foundation activities in water management (Reports 011116), 1987 (Box 445)
  Irrigation -- Research; Water -- Management; Irrigation projects; Agricultural development projects
- The Ford Foundation: Leadership in affecting poverty, 1987 Mar. (Reports 011117) (Box 445)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's programs on persistent poverty. Presented at March 1987 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
  Mid-Decade review
  Education, Secondary -- United States; Community development corporations -- United States; Poverty -- Research -- United States; Youth -- Employment -- United States
- Land resources: a review of Foundation activities in land management (Reports 011118), 1987 (Box 445)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's programs in agriculture and natural resources. Presented at the March 1987 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
  Land use, Rural; Natural resources -- Management
- Rural poverty and land management: a report on the Ford Foundation's work in social forestry, agroforestry and related activities, 1987 Jan. (Reports 011119) (Box 445)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's programs in agriculture and natural resources. Presented at March 1987 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
  Board of Trustees; Developing Countries Program/Rural Poverty and Resources; United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  ca. 189 p.
  Agroforestry; Social forestry programs; Natural resources -- Management
- Rural poverty and agriculture: a report on the Ford Foundation's work in agroecosystems and farming systems research, 1987 Jan. (Reports 011120) (Box 445)
  ca. 108 leaves.
  Agricultural ecology; Agricultural productivity; Agriculture -- Research; Biotic communities
- Helping poor farmers: a review of Foundation activities in farming systems and agroecosystems research and development, 1987 Jan. (Reports 011121) (Box 445)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's programs on agriculture and natural resources. Presented at the March 1987 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
- Rural poverty and water resources: a report on the Ford Foundation's work in water management, 1987 Mar. (Reports 011122-001) (Box 446)
  ca. 225 p.
  Irrigation -- Social aspects; Water -- Management
- Rural poverty and water resources: a report on the Ford Foundation's work in water management (Reports 011122-002), 1987 (Box 446)
  Water -- Management; Irrigation
- A major challenge of the 1960's: establishment of a sound relationship between the world's developed and less-developed nations (Reports 011124) (Box 446)
  International relations -- Developing countries
- Postdoctoral fellowship for minorities program: Outcomes study University of Wisconsin (Reports 011125), 1987 (Box 446)
  Education, Higher -- Blacks; Minorities -- Development -- Education
- Study of economic and business journalism for the Ford Foundation: Harvard (Reports 011126), 1987 (Box 446)
  [200] p.
  Education -- Journalism; Journalism, Educational
- Indonesian archaeology and related issues: University Museum (Reports 011127), 1987 (Box 446)
  [26] p.
  Archaeology -- Asia; Education -- Asia; Museum techniques -- Asia
- The Ford Foundation's Latin American program (Reports 011128-001), 1986 (Box 446)
  Prepared for discussion at the March 1986 meeting of the Board of Trustees. It is part of an update to a discussion paper presented to the Board in March 1984. See also Reports #008856.
  Board of Trustees; Developing Countries Program/Brazil; Developing Countries Program/Argentia and the Southern Cone; Developing Countries Program/Mexico and Central America
  90 p.: map, tables, charts -- 28 cm.
- The Ford Foundation's Latin American and Caribbean Program: (discussion paper): the Board of Trustees (Reports 011128-002), 1986 (Box 446)
  Developing Countries Program/Board of Trustees
  Ford Foundation activities -- Latin America and Caribbean Program; Latin American and Caribbean programs
- Drugs: the problems and the options: summary report to the Ford Foundation, 1987 (Reports 011129) (Box 446)
  Prepared for discussion at the June 1987 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
  87 leaves.
  Drug abuse -- Social aspects; Drug abuse -- Prevention
- The mid-decade review of the Ford Foundation's Program on Education and Culture (Reports 011130), 1987 (Box 446)
  A report prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's Program on Education and Culture Program. --T.p.
  Board of Trustees; United States and International Affairs Program/Education and Culture; Developing Countries Program/Education and Culture
  40 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Educational anthropology -- Study and teaching; Cultural property -- Protection; Education, Higher
- The Ford Foundation: pluralism and diversity (Reports 011131), 1987 (Box 446)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade review of the Ford Foundation's programs on Diversity and Equal Opportunity. --T.p.
  Board of Trustees; United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance; Developing Countries Program/Human Rights and Governance
  51 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Pluralism (Social sciences) -- United States; Political participation -- United States; Minorities -- United States -- Political activity
- Encouraging stability, peace and justice in the international order (Reports 011132), 1987 (Box 447)
  Prepared for the Mid-decade Review of the Ford Foundation's programs on International Affairs and International Human Rights. --T.p.
  Board of Trustees; Developing Countries Program/International Affairs; United States and International Affairs Program/International Affairs; Developing Countries Program/Human Rights and Governance; United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance
  2 v.: 65 leaves + appendices: tables, charts -- 28 cm.
  Past and future of international security studies
  Conference on International Economics and Development (1987 Apr. 13: Institute for International Economics, New York, NY)
  Human rights; International relations; International organization
- History of the Ford Foundation's International Affairs Program: draft no. 2, December 3 (Reports 011133), 1965 (Box 447)
  82 p. -- 28 cm.
  International relations -- Endowments -- History; International organization
- Evaluation of grant 61-189 to the University of the Valley for the development of a school of basic studies and improvement of secondary school science teaching (Reports 011134), 1970 (Box 447)
  17 p. + attachments.
  Education -- Latin America; Education -- International cooperation
- Some personal notes toward a history of the graduate program (escolatina), 1957-1964 (Reports 011135), 1972 (Box 447)
  Education -- Latin America; Education -- International affairs; Education, Higher
- Review of certain regular grants and the special appropriation (1966) of the Ford Foundation to Delhi University (Reports 011136), 1975 (Box 447)
  Report is a review of a number of projects and programs sponsored by The Ford Foundation at Delhi University over the decade 1964-1974.
  07200117
  The University Of Delhi
  70 p.
  Education, Higher -- India; Universities and colleges -- India -- Administration
- Economic sanctions and South Africa (Reports 011137), 1987 (Box 447)
  Offered as Master's Project in the Department of Political Science at New York University.
  Economic sanctions; Apartheid
- Water management: Concepts and issues paper: Prepared for Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Reports 011138), 1983 (Box 447)
  Provides a framework for discussion of issues, strategies and prospects for the Foundation's worldwide work in irrigation and water management.
  Developing Countries Program; India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Irrigation; Water-supply
- Agricultural productivity, concepts and issues paper: Pepared for Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Reports 011139), 1983 (Box 447)
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects; Agricultural development projects
- People and common property resources in land: Concept and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Reports 011140), 1983 (Box 447)
  Land management; Land use
- Rural community development: Role of community-based and intermediary organization: Concepts and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resourses Program (Reports 011141), 1983 (Box 447)
  Rural development; Organization and management
- Improving rural employment and incomes: Concept and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Reports 011142), 1983 (Box 447)
  Discussion of recent Foundation programs regarding off-farm employment as an important income and employment source for the rural poor.
  Labor supply -- Asia
- Rural social sciences and policy: concepts and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Reports 011143), 1983 (Box 447)
  Sociology, Rural -- Study and teaching
- Irrigation and the land-poor: paper prepared for presentation at the International Conference on Food and Water, Texas A and M University (Reports 011145), 1985 (Box 447)
  Irrigation development; Poverty; Water -- Management
- Report to the Ford Foundation on Cairo field office consultancy on human rights in the Middle East (Reports 011146), 1987 (Box 447)
  United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance; MEA
  Human rights -- Middle East
- Study of economic and business journalism for the Ford Foundation by the Foundation for American Communications: Harvard University (Reports 011147), 1987 (Box 447)
  08450964
  Journalism, Educational
- Education and development: Key issues for policy makers (Reports 011148), 1963 (Box 447)
  Paper offered at 3rd National Conference of the Canadian National Commission for UNESCO in Ottawa, Mar. 26-29, 1963.
  National Conference of the Canadian National Commission for UNESCO (3rd: 1963 Mar. 26-29: Ottawa)
  Educational planning -- Congresses
- Regional development planning and the Ford Foundation in Indonesia (Reports 011149), 1976 (Box 447)
  This is a memo found in PA76-343 grant file studying the FF possibility of making this a grant making activity.
  07600343
  Rural development
- Visit to Nigeria, November 1-8 (Reports 011150), 1976 (Box 447)
  p. 21.
  Agriculture -- Africa, West
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Supporting Materials, Volumes I and II, Program Evaluations, 1951-1961, Program Proposals for the 1960s (Reports 011151)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions I and II, Special Committee on Program Review (Reports 011152), 1962
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions III and IV, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 3 (Reports 011153)
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions V and VI, Special Committee on Program Review (Reports 011154), 1962
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions VII and VIII, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 17 (Reports 011155)
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions IX and X, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 April 13 (Reports 011156)
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Proceedings, Sessions XI and XII, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 April 14 (Reports 011157)
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Program Submission Concerning Future Program Activities, The Ford Foundation Special Committee, 1962 Spring (Reports 011158)
- The Ford Foundation in the 1960s, Statement of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations (Reports 011159), 1962
- The Role of the Foundation in American Society. W. McNeil Lowry, Director, Program in Humanities and the Arts, The Ford Foundation, The Nassau Club, Princeton (Reports 011160), 1958
- Address by John J. McCloy, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York, 1961 December 6 (Reports 011161)
- The Road to Peace, An Address by John J. McCloy, Counsel, Milbank, Tweed, Hope and Hadley, New York, 1961 November 29 (Reports 011162)
- Public Affairs Program (Reports 011163), 1958 (Box 448)
  32 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Law and the social sciences -- United States; Sociological jurisprudence
- Indicators for understanding: a profile of metro Chicago's immigrant community. (Reports 011164), 1995 (Box 448)
  52 p.: ill.; 28 cm.
  Emigration and immigration -- Chicago (Ill.) -- Statistics; Emigration and immigration -- Illinois -- Statistics; Ethnic groups -- Chicago (Ill.) -- Statistics; Ethnic groups -- Illinois -- Statistics
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic: program proposals for the fiscal year 1963 (Reports 011165) (Box 448)
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic: program proposals for the fiscal year 1962 (Reports 011166) (Box 448)
- Professional service in support of special purpose housing, November 4 (Reports 011167), 1963 (Box 448)
  5 p. - 28 cm.
  Housing; Housing -- Endowments
- Continued support of selected experimental programs in urban research, education and extension (Reports 011168), 1963 (Box 448)
  5 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Cities and towns -- Research -- United States; Community development, Urban -- United States; Education, Urban -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Improving the administration of justice (Reports 011169), 1962 (Box 448)
  Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States
- The Ford Foundation Program in Argentina and Chile, Sept. (Reports 011170), 1963 (Box 448)
  Philanthropy -- Argentina; Philanthropy -- Chile
- A review of political, administrative and economic trends in India and Nepal (Reports 011171), 1961 (Box 448)
  16 leaves + attachments: ill., graphs, tables -- 28 cm.
- The Ford Foundation's program in Argentina and Chile (Reports 011172), 1963 (Box 448)
  Technical assistance -- Argentina; Technical assistance -- Chile; Endowments -- Argentina -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Chile -- Evaluation
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan Program review and status report (Reports 011173), 1961 (Box 448)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Pakistan
- Ford Foundation supported activities in Indonesia: status report (Reports 011174), 1961 (Box 448)
  Technical assistance -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation
- Special education program for the Arab states (Reports 011175), 1954 (Box 448)
- Research: analysis and review (Reports 011176), 1953 (Box 448)
  Foreign study -- United States; Area studies -- United States
- Overseas Development Program: Pakistan: plans and estimates, January 1956 to (Reports 011177) (Box 448)
  34 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- India -- Finance; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Finance; Philanthropy -- Pakistan -- Finance; Philanthropy -- India -- Finance
- How the Near East Program is planned (Reports 011178), 1956 (Box 448)
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Budget and program review (Reports 011179), 1955 (Box 448)
  iii, 23 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- Pakistan program projections and budget 1961-62 through 1965-66 (Reports 011180), 1962 (Box 448)
  26 leaves + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- India Program budget for 1960-61 (Reports 011181) (Box 448)
  Analysis of current situation in India and description of existing and proposed projects.
  Subsidies -- India
- Near East Program summaries (Reports 011182), 1955 (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated November 16, 1955.
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Pakistan Program budget (Reports 011183), 1958 (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated December 22, 1958.
  6 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
- Pakistan Program projection (Reports 011184), 1954 (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated September 1, 1954.
- Pakistan Program projections (Reports 011185), 1955 (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated January 11, 1955.
  36 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
- India Program: memo (Reports 011186), 1954 (Box 448)
  Update of India program for 1954-1956 planning period.
- Pakistan Program problems (Reports 011187), 1958 (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated August 30, 1958.
- Pakistan Program budget: your letter of April 12, 1960 (Reports 011188) (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated April 26, 1960.
- India Program standard report. No. 1: status of active grants as of July 15 (Reports 011189), 1960 (Box 448)
  List of active grants by the India Field Office.
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s: proceedings (Reports 011190), 1962 (Box 450, Box 449)
  Notes on Sessions I-XII.
  4 v.: var. pag -- 28 cm.
- The role of the Foundation in American society: Princeton (Reports 011191), 1958 (Box 450)
  Speech given at the Nassau Club in Princeton, N.J.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Social aspects; Philanthropy -- United States
- Address: United States Military Academy, West Point, New York (Reports 011192), 1961 (Box 450)
  Disarmament; Peace; Democracy
- Conversations and correspondence with American and international leaders and experts (Reports 011193), 1962
  [New York]: Ford Foundation, 1962.
  Ford Foundation's policy, program and operational directives for the 1960s: vol. III.
  International relations; Ford Foundation
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s (Reports 011193-001), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume I: Ford Foundation Program Evaluation (Reports 011193-002), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume II: Trustee and Staff Proposals for Ford Foundation Programs for the 1960s (Reports 011193-003), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume III: Conversations and Correspondence with American and International Leaders and Experts (Reports 011193-004), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume IV: Special Papers and Working Documents (Reports 011193-005), 1962 (Box 451)
- Rural poverty and resources (Reports 011194), 1984 (Box 451)
  New York worldwide actual FY 1984 and expected FY 1985 budget allocations. --p. [1].
  5 p. + attachments; tables -- 28 cm.
  Developing Country Programs: FY 1985 Program Reviews: New York, International Affairs
  Rural poor -- Developing countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries
- Changing emphases in the Ford Foundation's population work (Reports 011195), 1984 (Box 451)
  For discussion at the December 1984 Trustees' Meeting. -T.p.
  43 p.+ attachments: tables
  Population research -- Developing countries; Population assistance -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Developing countries
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews, New York: International Affairs (Reports 011196), 1984 (Box 451)
  Developing Countries Program/International Affairs
  11 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  International relations; International economic relations; Security, International; Arms control
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews: Brazil (Reports 011197), 1984 (Box 451)
  39 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews: China and other Asia (Reports 011198), 1984 (Box 451)
  Developing Countries Program/China
  Technical assistance -- China; Endowments -- China -- Evaluation
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 rapporteur notes (Reports 011199), 1984 (Box 451)
  This report contains ten program reviews by each of the program offices dealing with hers/his respective field in DCP.
  p. 53.
  Human rights and governance; International relations; Rural poverty and resourses; Urban poverty; Women
- U.S. foreign policy: discussion paper at the meeting of the Trustees' Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee (Reports 011200), 1983 (Box 451)
  International Affairs/Human Rights and Governance
  p. 54.
  International relations -- United States
- Annual program status report: Pakistan, fiscal year (Reports 011202), 1973 (Box 451)
  Program reports, supplements, and budget projections for the year.
  Overseas Division/South and Southeast Asia; International Division/Asia and the Pacific
  07191366
  22 p. + appendices
  Philanthropy -- Pakistan
- The road to peace an address by (Reports 011203), 1961 (Box 451)
  Disarmament; Peace; World politics
- The quality of the doctorate in schools of education: a final report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011204), 1985 (Box 451)
  Urban Poverty program
  08450155
  Northwestern University
  [116] p.; 28 cm.
  Doctor of education degree
- Conservation of manuscripts at Varendra Research Museum, Rajshahi: Final report including report on Dhaka University Library (Reports 011205), 1985 (Box 451)
  Manuscripts -- Conservation and restoration
- An evaluation of two Ford Foundation grants: PA770-0093 and PA845-0643 (Reports 011206), 1985
  Education -- Colombia
- Modeling the environmental effects of forest management in a watershed: A multi-objective approach to forest management for developing countries (Reports 011207), 1981 (Box 451)
  Forest management -- Developing countries
- Specification of rural electrification analysis (Reports 011208), 1981 (Box 451)
- Innovation in political communication: the sound broadcasting of parliamentary proceedings (Reports 011209), 1978 (Box 451)
  United States and International Affairs Program
  L78-147.
  Communication in politics
- The intervention of television in British politics (Reports 011210), 1975 (Box 451)
  Television and politics -- Great Britain; Mass media -- Research -- Great Britain
- The role of theory in uses and gratifications studies (Reports 011211), 1977 (Box 451)
  Mass media
- Agricultural production, distribution and consumption: An interim program document for agriculture and rural development in Brazil, 1978-1980 (Reports 011212) (Box 452)
  L78-143
  Agriculture; Rural development -- Brazil
- Environmental training in developing countries: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011213), 1980 (Box 452)
  L80-86
  Ecology -- Developing countries
- Strategies to increase mathematics enrollments (Reports 011214), 1980 (Box 452)
  L80-131
  Women -- Education -- Mathematics
- Sex differences in mathematics (Reports 011215), 1980 (Box 452)
- Services: A new look at the U.S. economy (Reports 011216), 1980 (Box 452)
  L80-143
  iii, [154] leaves -- 28 cm.
- Sugar or alcohol?: a billion dollar Brazilian question (Reports 011217), 1980 (Box 452)
  Alcohol as fuel -- Brazil
- Direct biomass combustion potentials for industrial and electric generation applications in LDCs (Reports 011218), 1981 (Box 452)
  Biomass energy -- Developing countries; Power resources -- Developing countries -- Economic aspects; Energy consumption -- Developing countries; Agriculture and energy -- Developing countries
- Charcoal industry location and transport study (Reports 011219), 1981 (Box 452)
  Fuel trade; Charcoal industry